

LOCATION



Birmingham, Al

SKILLS

- Web Design
- HTML / CSS / JavaScript / Python
- Front End / Back End
- · Problem-Solving
- Computer Literacy
- Project Management Tools
- Strong Communication

EDUCATION

HIGH SCHOOL

Arnold High School 2000-2004

FULL STACK DEVELOPER CERTIFICATE

Bottega University 2022

CODE/ PROJECTS



https://github.com/usmc1371nerd



https://glasspandaeats.com

JAMES **DUMAS**

JUNIOR DEVELOPER

PROFILE

Experienced Junior Engineer with proficiency in JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, and React, backed by completion of Bottega University's full-stack development course. Strong project management and time management skills with a demonstrated ability to quickly learn new concepts. Served honorably for over a decade in the military.

EXPERIENCE

ASSOCIATE ENGINEER (CONTRACTOR)

Nibuild

2023 - Present

- Develop and implemented code for database management and optimization.
- Lead website development projects using KoPage, ensuring mobile responsiveness and updates.
- Participated in standup meetings and utilized GitLab/ Github for version control. Worked in a collaborative environment to develop solutions to problems.

TEACHING ASSOCIATE (PART TIME)

Bottega University (Full Stack Development Certificate)
2023- Present

- Facilitate comprehension of course material and assist students with coding exercises.
- Research and provide updated information on software development best practices.
- Support instructor in delivering high-quality education in full-stack development.
- Graded capstone projects and did code reviews 1 on 1 with students

MILITARY AWARDS

Army Achievement Medal, Navy Unit
Citation, Navy Meritorious Unit Citation,
Marine Good Conduct Medal x 2, National
Defense Service Medal, Afghanistan
Campaign, Iraq Campaign Medal, Global
War on Terrorism, Humanitarian Service
Medal, Sea Service Deployment Ribbon x 3,
Florida NG Meritorious Service Ribbon,
Florida NG Active Service Ribbon

MILITARY LEADERSHIP DEVELOPMENT

2007 Corporals Course (USMC)

Leadership development program modeled after military training, focused on honing essential leadership skills and principles. Topics included effective communication, decision-making, team management, and ethical leadership. Graduated with strengthened leadership abilities, ready to excel in roles requiring strong organizational and interpersonal skills.

2008 Sergeants Course (USMC)

A comprehensive leadership development program emphasizing advanced leadership principles and practical skills. Topics covered include strategic decision-making, team building, conflict resolution, and personnel management. Graduated with enhanced leadership capabilities and readiness to excel in roles requiring strategic thinking, effective communication, and team management skills.

DELIVERY DRIVER, AND SALES ASSOCIATE (PART-TIME)

R&W Wholesale

2022 - Present

- Assisting customers with their flower orders for events.
- Delivering product to a customer by managing my time on the route to the customer needs.
- Learning the product we sell, and learning any new product to help assist the customer with any questions.

INDEPENDENT CONTRACTOR, PROJECT MANAGEMENT, AND CONSULTING

2022-2023

- Reading any and all blueprints to also include any customer input or changes and using best building practices to manage the build of homes.
- Keeping up to date on all building codes pertaining to residential building and passing building inspections.
- Setting timelines for multiple different sub-contractors to help maintain deadlines for the overall build.

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

Holland Homes

2021-2022

- Reading any and all blueprints to also include any customer input or changes and using best building practices to manage the build of homes.
- Keeping up to date on all building codes pertaining to residential building.
- Sending invoices and creating change orders for custom home builds, and managing the budgets of all builds under my charge.

JP'S HOME SOLUTIONS, BUSINESS OWNER

Owner

2018-2021

- Completed estimates, set up deliveries of materials, and managed job time frames.
- Worked with clients and their visions to build a product that they wanted from fencing, custom on site builds, and small home remodels.
- Invoiced customers on work performed, wrote contracts, and completed all work myself.